Samuel M. Corwin

1230 Wingding Ridge Terrace | Colorado Springs, CO 80919 https://smcorwin.github.io/ | (719) 502-6693 | samuelcorwin4@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Renewable energy market and policy analyst with strong research, writing, and verbal communication skills (in English and Mandarin Chinese). Motivated to use proven qualitative and quantitative problem-solving abilities to be part of a team working to develop and implement clean energy solutions.

Professional Experience

Fulbright U.S. Student Program, Nanjing, China

Fulbright Research Fellow, Fall 2017-present

- Identified shortcomings in China's domestic solar PV energy market that result from excessive local government influence.
- Analyzed factors contributing to market deficiencies, such as overproduction and curtailment, based on an investigation of electricity market reforms, policy changes, and manufacturing and installation data.
- Synthesizing the findings of factors impeding solar market development in a report that will be completed in August 2018.

Asia Society Northern California, Nanjing, China

Co-Author and Analyst, Nov. 2017-present

- Co-authoring a report identifying opportunities for clean technology collaboration between the U.S. and China.
- Identified commercial case studies of clean technology collaboration, with a focus on market access, finance and investment, and R&D.
- Analyzed barriers to entry for private Chinese and American clean technology companies seeking to access each other's market.

Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC), Washington, D.C.,

Energy Efficiency for All (EEFA) Fellow, Summer 2016

- Spearheaded a project examining how to integrate solar PV with energy efficiency upgrades in affordable multifamily housing by analyzing barriers, policy, financial opportunities, and evaluating program states for pilot project suitability.
- Proposed and completed a report identifying gaps in EEFA and presented findings to partner organizations to guide implementation.

Clean Energy Associates (CEA), Shanghai, China

Supply Chain Management Intern, Fall 2015

- Produced an analysis and manufacturing recommendation of a new solar module technology based on efficiency and market compatibility.
- Completed competitive analysis research enabling CEA to identify major competitors and their business models.
- Developed strategic planning resources based on the global solar supply chain, focusing on policy in Japan and Mexico.

Population Connection, Washington, D.C.

Population Education Stanback Fellow, Summer 2015

- Developed and analyzed content that was implemented in interactive environmental education resources (https://goo.gl/f0xKk1).
- Collaborated with my supervisor to create curriculum guides that are currently being utilized in high school environmental classes across the U.S.

Other Relevant Experience

Energy Reports and Carbon Pricing, Bass Connections, Duke University

Fall 2016-Spring 2017

Graduated: May 2017

- Convinced Duke administration to implement campus-wide educational programs and distribute departmental energy reports that we designed.
- Lead author of a report of recommendations presented to Duke's Executive VP about an internal carbon pricing model and educational programs.
- Collaborated with a team of faculty and students to identify strategies for reducing on-campus energy consumption based on expertise in carbon pricing and capital investment decision-making.

Duke University Campus Sustainability Committee, Combined Heat and Power (CHP) Plant Subcommittee

Spring 2017

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary group of stakeholders to advise Duke's Board of Trustees on a proposed on-campus 21 MW CHP plant.
- Contributed to evaluation of financial feasibility, biogas, and alternatives based on electrical generation economics and campus power networks.

Education |

Duke University, Durham, NC | GPA: 3.73

- Double Major: Environmental Science/Policy, Asian & Middle Eastern Studies (Chinese concentration)
- Environmental Science Department Independent Study: "The Growth and Development of China's Solar PV Market"
- Fudan University (Boston University), Shanghai, China: advanced Mandarin Chinese study with renewable energy internship

Duke Summer in China, Beijing, China: Mandarin Chinese language immersion program | GPA: 3.7

Fall 2015

Summer 2014

Honors & Awards

- J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship for China, 2017-2018; CET-Harbin Critical Language Enhancement Award, 2017
- Duke University Fall 2013 Dean's List, Fall 2014 Dean's List, Spring 2016 Dean's List with Distinction
- Air Academy High School Senior Speaker; graduated Summa Cum Laude (4.6+ GPA), 2013
- 2012 Boulder Marathon: finished first place in the 16-19 age group

Skills & Interests

- Renewable Energy Stengths: Solar PV, market development, supply chain, barriers to entry, policy analysis, deployment strategies, vendor analysis
- Skills: Leadership and teamwork ability, creative problem solving, excellent presentation and written communication skills, analytical research
- Foreign Languages: Advanced Mandarin Chinese (reading, speaking, and writing), proficient Spanish
- Software: Microsoft Office (including Excel, PowerPoint, and Word), Python, Adobe Premier Elements, Photoshop, Final Cut Pro
- Interests: Photography, snowboarding, running, hiking, social justice, sports, and volunteer work